HAFEN&远鉴字幕组联合制作
翻译：未雨绸缪 ChattyC 第七键盘侠 小草莓 源宝biubiu
光
Light.
到达目的地要上百万年
It can travel for millions of years before finally reaching its destination.
它独自且孤单的飘荡着
It goes lonely and alone...
希望着能够到达目的地
hoping that it will reach someone.
但是如果光永远无法到达目的地呢
But what if it never arrives?
如果永远找不到家呢
What if it never finds a home?
因为宇宙太大了
Because space is so vast...
时间太长了
and time is so long...
在那里 很容易会找不到出路
and out here, it's so easy to get lost.
全体注意 全体注意
All hands alert. All hands alert.
辐射程度迅速攀升
Radiation levels climbing.
35%
35 percent.
提升防护
Raise shields.
防护下降了60%
Shields are down to 60 percent.
还在继续下降
Still falling.
敬请稍后
我能看一下吗 这辐射是从哪来的
Can I get a reading? Where is this coming from?
生命支持装置受到影响
Life support has been compromised.
重复 生命支持装置受到了影响
I repeat, life support has been compromised.
舰长的日志 最后的记录
Captain's log, final entry.
企业号被认定失踪了
The Enterprise is presumed lost.
斯波克和我是唯一的幸存者
Spock and I are the sole survivors.
我们的命运 未知
Our destiny, unknown.
我不行了 斯波克
I'm not gonna make it, Spock.
你必须坚持下去 独自一人拯救联邦号
You have to go on and save the Federation alone.
不 舰长
Negative, Captain.
没有你 我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere without you.
斯波克呼叫企业号
Spock to Enterprise.
企业号 我是斯波克
"Enterprise, this is Spock."
企业号 你们在吗
"Enterprise, are you there?"
哦 说你看见的
♪ Oh, say can you see ♪
在清晨的阳光下
♪ By the dawn's early light ♪
我们骄傲的欢呼
♪ What so proudly we hailed ♪
嗨 莱克斯
Hey, Lexi.
在傍晚最后的霞光中
♪ At the twilight's last gleaming ♪
它广阔的条纹和闪亮的星星
♪ Whose broad stripes and bright stars ♪
通过险恶的战争
♪ Through the perilous fight ♪
我是斯卡特林·凯尔
This is Scotlyn Kyle
在港湾区支持救援中心
at the Bay Area Assisted Living Center.
请留信息
Please leave a message.
嗨 大D
Hey, Big D.
还有那石头上红色的闪光
♪ And the rockets' red glare ♪
女士们
Ladies.
过来 布里特妮 给我一个拥抱
Come here, Brittanie, give me a hug.
哦 早上好
Oh, good morning.
辛迪
Cindy...
击掌
High-five.
很好 很疼
Nice one! That hurt!
嗨 温迪在哪
Hey, where's Wendy?
我想她在她楼上卧室里
I think she's upstairs in her bedroom.
星条旗是否还在飘扬
♪ Say does that star-spangled banner yet wave ♪
在这片自由的土地上
♪ Over the land of the free ♪
坚持住 舰长
"Hang on, Captain...
我会送你回家的
I am going to get you home."
- 早上好 温迪  - 早上好 斯卡特林
- Good morning, Wendy. - Good morning, Scottie.
好的
Okay.
我们能试试三秒钟对视吗
Can we try three seconds of eye contact?
试试吧 就三秒
Let's try... three seconds.
好的 三秒种目光对视
Great. Three seconds of eye contact.
好
Yay.
你的姐姐下个星期要来看你
So, next week, your sister's coming to visit.
你有什么感觉
How are you feeling about it?
请大点声
Out loud thinking, please.
我感觉有一点紧张
I'm feeling somewhat a little bit nervous.
那是什么感觉
What does that feel like?
像是我想去小便 但又尿不出来
Like I've got to pee, but I don't.
我紧张时也有相似的感觉
That's how nervousness feels for me, too.
但是 你知道吗 根本没必要去担心
But, you know, there's no need to worry,
我们会确保你充分做好准备
we're gonna make sure you're very well-prepared.
好了 现在 我们能复习一下你的每天日程吗
Okay, now, can we go over your everyday schedule?
我的每天日程
My everyday schedule...
起床
Wake up.
整理床铺
Make bed.
收拾毛巾和化妆品
Get towel and toiletries.
如果我的毛巾有异味
If my towel smells funny,
把它扔进洗衣桶并且拿一条新毛巾
put it in the hamper and get a new towel.
进卫生间
Go into bathroom.
检查我是否到了生理期
Check to see if I'm having my period.
如果我来潮了
If I am having my period,
记住我的生理期
remember that I am having my period.
你如何做
And how do you do that?
我竖起大拇指来帮我记忆
I put one thumb up to help me remember.
如果我来潮了 贴上卫生纸
If I am having my period, put on a Kotex maxi pad,
再把大拇指放下
and put my thumb down.
穿上一件外衣
Put on an outfit.
星期一 橘色
Monday, orange.
星期二 薰衣草色
Tuesday, lavender.
星期三 蓝色
Wednesday, blue.
星期四 斑点
Thursday, dots.
星期五 黄色
Friday, yellow.
星期六 紫色
Saturday, purple.
星期天 红色
Sunday is red.
进厨房去做烤面包
Go into the kitchen to make toast.
除非理查德那张讨厌的脸霸占着烤面包机
Unless Richard "the Fuck Face" is hogging the toaster.
温迪
Wendy.
除非理查德霸占着烤面包机
Unless Richard is hogging the toaster.
去上班
Go to work.
在页面街向右转
Turn right onto Page Street.
在布坎南街向右转
Turn right onto Buchanan Street.
当我到市场街的时候 停下
And when I get to Market Street, stop...
因为我在任何情况下都不准通过这条街
Because I'm not allowed to cross Market Street under any circumstances.
等321号公交车去斯通镇广场车站
Wait for the 321 Bus to Stonestown Galleria.
记住在工作时微笑 当我说
Remember to smile at work, while I say...
欢迎来到肉桂卷店 你要来点肉桂卷吗
Welcome to Cinnabon! Would you like a Cinnabon?
不要将这句话重复的太快
But don't repeat the words too quickly.
而且每次试着换一个语调
And make it sound different each time.
欢迎来到肉桂卷店 你要来点肉桂卷吗
Welcome to Cinnabon. Would you like a Cinnabon?
Welcome to Cinnabon! Would you like a Cinnabon?
下午 三点 学习
Three pm, study.
好的 看他的嘴是怎么向下的
Yeah, see how his mouth goes down?
- 好的  - 四点 带皮特散步
- Okay. - Four pm, take Pete for a walk.
当你看见一个有腿的人时 这说明你可以走了
When you see the man with the legs, it means you can walk.
当你看见一个红色的手时
When you see the red hand,
这说明在走之前你必须举起你的手等待着
it means that you have to hold up your hand before you can walk.
六点 在电视上看星际迷航
Six pm, watch "Star Trek" on TV Land.
飞船仍然可以运行 舰长
The ship is still functioning, Captain.
我们可以合理推测
It is logical to assume
叛变者在船上的某处
the mutineers are somewhere aboard.
七点 晚饭
7:00 pm, dinner.
八点 家务
8:00 pm, chores.
在睡觉前 我有自由活动的时间
And then I have free time before I go to bed.
很好
Beautiful.
我想你姐姐会很吃惊的
I think your sister's gonna be very impressed.
- 我想她也会  - 换做是我会吃惊的
- I think she will be, too. - I would be.
我很吃惊
I am.
好的 现在是复习你的 名字和地方 的时候了
Okay, now it's time to work on your "Names and Places".
名字和地方 很糟糕
"Names and Places" sucks!
是的 我也不喜欢这项活动
Well, it's not my favorite activity either,
但是我们得做
but we need to do it.
我能看电视吗
Can I watch TV?
能
Yes.
但是首先 你必须如何
But first, what do you have to be?
你必须非常
You have to be very...
冷静
Calm.
很好
Excellent.
要咖啡吗
Coffee?
好的 谢谢
Yes, please!
见鬼 没牛奶了
Shit, no milk.
是吗
Yeah?
保佑你
Ah, bless you.
谢谢
Thanks.
你什么时候去见你的妹妹
When are you seeing your sister?
马上
Soon.
咖啡不错
Mm, that's good.
现在 一个重要的提醒
And now, an important reminder...
50年以来
For 50 years,
探索星际之旅已经到达从来没有到达的地方
Star Trek has boldly gone where no one has gone before.
所以 通话结束了 竞争开始了
So, the call is out and the contest is on.
他们希望你送来你的剧本
They want you to send in your script,
凸显出星际之旅宇宙中最好的部分
highlighting the best of the Star Trek universe.
让你的文字处理器动起来吧
So, fire up those word processors
因为你的完整的 打印出来的剧本
because your completed, printed script
必须在2月16日之前被高级部门收到
must be received by Paramount no later than February 16th.
把你的剧本写完吧 就剩一个星期了
So, get your scripts done, it's just one week away.
他站在了现实的边缘
"He stood there, on the edge of reality...
只有一层薄薄的隔膜
Only a thin membrane
把他和混乱分隔开
shielded him from the chaos beyond...
他能相信沃尔夫指挥官吗
Could he trust Commander Worf or not?
他问他自己
He asked himself.
他怕最糟糕的事情发生
He feared the worst.
斯波克抬头看了一下布满星星的天空
Spock looks up at the star-filled sky,
探索了一下这片荒芜的外星土地
surveys the barren contours of this alien wasteland...
逃跑势在必行 他低语道
'Escape is imperative,' he whispers."
嗨 温迪
Hey, Wendy.
嗨 尼莫
Hi, Nemo.
- 你的剧本写得怎么样了  - 写的很好
- How's your script coming? - It's going excellent.
我刚刚写了一个支线剧情
I just wrote a sub-story
斯波克深入到了第九宇宙区
where Spock travels to Deep Space Nine
来邀请沃尔夫指挥官一起参加战争
to recruit Commander Worf for battle.
听起来很好
That sounds awesome.
顺便 我
By the way, I...
我给你做了点东西
I made you something.
这个得到了很好的评论
It's got some really dope tracks on there.
我希望你能喜欢它
I really hope you enjoy it.
我去清洗搅拌机
I'm gonna clean the mixer.
哦 说你看见的
♪ Oh, say can you see ♪
理查德 我们给你安排一场面试
So, Richard, we've arranged an interview for you
在街尾的杂货店
at the grocery store at the end of the street.
你感兴趣吗
Does that interest you?
嗯
Yeah?
对不起
Excuse me.
你好
Hello?
- 是卡特林·凯尔吗  - 是
- Is this Scotlyn Kyle? - Yeah.
凯尔女士 我是来自巴尔博亚高中的雷金纳德·梅威瑟
Ms. Kyle, this is Reginald Mayweather from Balboa High.
你今天起床了吗
Did you get out of bed today?
彻底的
At all?
好吧
Okay.
你怎么了 山姆
What's going on with you, Sam?
你感到沮丧吗 愤怒吗
You ever feel depressed? Angry?
妈妈 别来诊断我
Mom, stop trying to diagnose me.
那么 你为什么没在上学
Well, why aren't you in school?
我们有个约定 你去学校 你好好学习
We had a deal. You go to school, you do well.
这就是我全部要求的
That's all I ask.
你下周有一个数学测验
And you have a math test next week which,
我今天才刚刚知道的
by the way, I just found out about today.
所以 年轻人 你给我在这学习
So, young man, you are gonna study right here.
我奶奶都能回答你愚蠢的问题
Even my grandmother could answer your stupid questions.
伙计 你也可以问她
Dude, you might as well be asking her
飞船的名字是什么
what the name of the ship is,
你找一个难一点的问题如何
how about you find a hard question?
比如在书的后几页
Like in the back of the book.
我有一个问题
I got one.
好
Okay.
在原版军事法庭那集中
In the original series episode, "Court Martial"...
斯波克先生获得了什么荣誉
what award was given to Mr. Spock?
瓦肯科学荣誉军团
The Vulcan Scientific Legion of Honor.
好了 交钱吧
Oh, snap! Pay up!
她一定作弊了
She's got to be cheating!
她有作弊的纸
She's got a cheat sheet.
她怎么作弊 你们挑的问题
How can she cheat, dog? You're picking the questions!
也许她把答案写在那些纸上
Maybe she's got the answers written on her papers!
看 看
Look, look.
【欠债作为赌注 赢了欠款抵消 输了翻倍的一种下注方式】
加倍或全无 再来吧
Double or nothing, then.
谁怕谁
Okay.
往后翻 往后找
Go deep, go deep.
找冷门的
Go deep.
医疗官伦纳德·麦考伊的女儿叫什么?
What was Dr. Leonard McCoy's daughter's name?
乔安娜
Joanna.
-什么? -你说什么?
- What's that? - What'd you say?
乔安娜
Joanna.
-我屮艸芔茻! -简直了!
- No way! - That's impossible!
她打败你们了!给钱吧!
She got you! Pay up, bitches!
两只弱鸡哈哈哈!
Suck it!
-拿着你的脏钱吧 -简直不是人
- Have your dirty money. - What the Spock.
搞不懂 唉 算了吧
I don't know, dude, suck it.
她到底怎么知道的...?
How did she know...?
你应该问寇克舰长的奶奶叫什么
Should've asked her what Kirk's grandma's name is.
叫什么?
What is Kirk's grandma's name?
"史波克凝视着幽暗的深渊
"Peering into the murky abyss...
看见了一个他从未见过的东西
Spock saw something he had never seen before.
一个窗口...
A window...
一扇通向另一个世界的时空门...
A portal to that other world...
不是什么幻觉
Not a vision,
也不是光线...
not a light...
而是一种感觉...
but a feeling...
一种他以前并不理解的感觉"
A feeling he didn't understand."
从不理解的...
...didn't understand.
惊叹
Wonderment.
斯考蒂 你可以看看我写的电影剧本么?
Scottie, will you read my movie script for me, please?
当然
Sure.
那你能尽快看完么?
Will you read it as soon as possible, please?
电影剧本都这么厚的吗？
Are movie scripts supposed to be this long?
是啊
Yes.
因为这是个史诗般的传奇来着
Because it's an epic saga,
它就应该很长 有丰富的细节
it should be long, highly detailed,
完整详尽
thorough.
在我的剧本里 史波克来回穿梭时间
In my script, Spock travels back and forth through time
去拯救联盟
to save the Federation.
哇 听起来很棒
Wow, sounds fascinating.
最后 有几段是用克林贡语写的
Towards the end, there are a few passages in the Klingon language,
不过别担心 到时候会有字幕的
but don't worry, there will be subtitles.
那就好
Good to know.
其实吧...我们还是可以带上它的
You know, we can still take it with us.
-放不下了 -好吧...
- No room. - Well...
那我们可以寄过去
We could have it shipped.
出不起邮费
We can't afford it.
你不是喜欢弹琴吗
I thought you loved playing.
我喜欢听温蒂弹
I liked it when Wendy played.
我去看看露比是不是醒了
I'm gonna go see if Ruby's awake yet.
嘿
Hey.
怎么了?
What?
tribble是什么
What's a "tribble"?
一种有点像豚鼠的东西
It's kind of like a guinea pig-type thing,
不过没有四肢 也没有脸
but without legs, or a face,
而且它繁殖速度快得吓人
and it reproduces like crazy.
温蒂
Wendy.
看仔细了
Pay attention. Look.
餐叉放左边 放餐巾上 餐叉在左
Fork goes on the left, right on top. Fork on the left.
到你了 你来试试
You try, your turn.
左边 把它放左边
On the left. Put it on the left.
对 做得好
Yeah, good job.
然后是餐刀
And the knife.
看到餐刀没?温蒂 看这里
You see the knife? Wendy, look at the knife.
它要放在右边
It goes on the right.
就像这样
Just like that.
你想试试摆盘子吗?
Wanna try the plate?
这个最简单了 摆在正中间就好
That one's easy, it goes right in the middle.
你可以的 试试吧
You can do it. Come on.
妈!
Mom!
别闹了!
Stop!
妈!
Mom!
你在看什么?
What are you watching?
♪ Hey, lio-lio-lio ♪
♪ Hey, lio-lilee-lio ♪
你想试试吗?
You wanna try?
厉害了 弹得对!
Yeah! You did it!
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee-lilee ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee lo ♪
真棒!
Good job!
"史波克抬头看着漫漫星空
"Spock looks up at the star-filled sky,
环顾着这片贫瘠的外星荒地
surveys the barren contours of this alien wasteland.
'史波克 必须得逃离了'他喃喃自语道..."
'Spock, escape is imperative,' he whispers..."
嘿 温蒂
Hey, Wendy.
明天是个大日子
Big day tomorrow.
在我走之前你还有什么需要的?
Anything you need before I go?
你读过我的剧本了么?
Have you read my script yet?
我正在看
I'm working on it.
-安 -晚安
- Night. - Good night.
谢谢您一直在帮助温蒂
Thank you for working with Wendy.
我知道她有时候很难相处
I know how difficult she can be.
实话跟您说吧 我很害怕
To tell you the truth, I'm scared.
温蒂变了
Wendy's changed.
来这儿以后 她有了巨大的进展
She's made huge strides since being here.
她进步很大
She's come such a long way.
你和她聊天就知道了
You'll see when you talk to her.
你俩单独聊吧
I'll leave you to it.
嗨 温蒂
Hi, Wendy.
嗨 奥德丽
Hi, Audrey.
-你看上去很不错 -谢谢
- You look nice. - Thank you.
我喜欢你的衣服
I like your outfit.
紫色好正啊
It's so purple.
听说你找到工作了
So, I heard you got a job.
你喜欢它吗?
Do you like it?
不 糟心死了 但至少我可以做肉桂卷
No, it sucks, but at least I get to make Cinnabons.
噢
Oh.
我给你带了张露比的照片
I brought you a picture of Ruby.
露比现在会什么了?
What can Ruby do now?
她会喊爸爸妈妈了
She can say "Mama" and "Dada"...
还会说埃尔默
and "Elmo".
她爱死埃尔默了
She loves Elmo.
我能留着这张照片么?
Can I have this picture of Ruby?
当然能 我就是给你带的
Yeah, I brought it for you.
我什么时候能见见露比?
When can I meet Ruby?
快了
Soon.
我是她小姨
I'm her aunt.
是这样的 温蒂 我今天来看你
So, Wendy, I came to visit today
是因为有事情要跟你说
because there's something I need to tell you.
呃 杰克终于找到新工作了
Um, Jack has finally found a new job and...
有个星际迷航的剧本写作比赛
There's a Star Trek script-writing contest.
啊 好吧 挺好的
Oh, okay, cool.
这个比赛的参赛者
It's a contest where they're having
要自己写星际迷航的电影剧本
people write their own Star Trek movie scripts
所以我写了个剧本
and I wrote a script.
哇!
Oh, wow!
今天就是投递截止日期了
Today is the last day to send it in,
但我想先确定它已经毫无问题了 再寄出去
but I didn't want to send it in until it was absolutely ready.
所以我检查来检查去
So, I double-checked and triple-checked,
搞了好多遍
and quadruple-checked,
现在 我可以把它寄出去了
and it's ready to go to the post office now.
要是现在寄走 刚好能掐着时间送到
So, if we mail it, it'll get there right on time.
剧本已经没问题了
It's ready to go.
所以 我们可以一起去邮局 然后我跟你一起回家
So, we can go to the post office and then I can go home with you.
温蒂 这件事我们已经谈过了
Wendy, we talked about this.
我获奖以后会有十万块奖金的
After I win, I'll have $100,000,
你也不用再照顾我了
and you won't have to take care of me anymore,
也不用卖掉妈妈留下来的房子
and you won't have to sell Mom's house.
但你在这里做得挺好的
But I don't want to take you out of here
我不想带你离开这里
when you're doing so good.
不是因为我不愿意 只是还不是时候
It's not that I don't want to, it's that it's not a good time.
你难道不喜欢这里吗?
Don't you like it here?
不喜欢 在这里就算我不喜欢
No, I have to eat pizza on Thursdays
周四我还是只能吃披萨
even if I don't want to.
我想看电视的时候也不让看
I can't watch TV when I want to.
我想写东西的时候也不能写
I can't write when I want to.
所以 我要和你一起回家了 奥德丽
So, I'm ready to go home with you now, Audrey.
温蒂 求你现在别这样好么
Wendy, please don't do this now.
我有工作了 我能自己去上班
I have a job now. I can get there all by myself.
不管你问什么 我都能回答正确
Ask me anything, I'll tell you the right answer.
求你了 别这样
Please, stop.
我现在可以自己照顾自己了
I can take care of myself now.
所以 我可以和你一起回家了
So, I'm ready to go home with you,
我还能帮你带露比啊
and I can help you take care of Ruby.
温蒂 你做不到的
Wendy, you can't.
你没办法照顾一个婴儿
You can't take care of a baby.
我怎么就不行?
How do you know?
你怎么就知道我不行?
How do you know I can't?
温蒂...
Wendy...
我现在可以回家了 奥德丽
I'm ready to go home now, Audrey.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我现在可以回家了
I'm ready to go home now.
斯科蒂!
Scottie!
你能帮我告诉奥德丽 告诉她我可以回家了么?
Can you please tell Audrey that I'm ready to go home now?
温蒂 没事的
Wendy, it's okay.
是你鼓动她这么做的?
Have you been encouraging this?
闭嘴
Shut up.
我们必须要讨论每个人的未来
We have to discuss everybody's future,
要考虑他们想去哪 有什么愿望
where they want to be, where they see themselves.
-她现在就住这儿啊 -别说了!
- This is where she lives now. - Shut up!
温蒂，我不觉得
Because Wendy, I don't think
-我能照顾好你 -别说了!
- I can take care of you. - Shut up!
你闭嘴!
Shut up!
温蒂 别这样
Wendy, please stop.
-闭嘴! -温蒂 停下来
- Shut up! - Wendy, stop.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
请稍候
Please stand by.
Please, stand by.
请稍候
请稍候 请稍候
Please, stand by. Please, stand by.
深呼吸
Breathe.
请稍候
Please, stand by.
深呼吸
Breathe.
这就对了 请稍候
That's it. Please stand by.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
请稍候
Please, stand by.
就是这样 请稍候
That's it. Please, stand by.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
请稍候
Please, stand by.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
温蒂
Wendy.
下午七点了
It's 7:00 pm.
别这样 我们还要继续你下一个日程呢
Come on, we have to move on to the next item in your schedule.
该吃晚饭啦
It's dinner time.
你要不要下楼去?今晚是辣酱通心粉呢
You wanna come downstairs? We're having chili mac.
你知道吗?
You know what?
要是你想的话
If you want,
今晚的家务时间你可以用来写作
you can skip chores tonight and write instead.
好吧 那...
Okay, well...
我们明天早上再聊
We can talk some more in the morning.
行吗 温蒂?
Okay, Wendy?
"剧本须完整 格式正确 且为打印稿
"Your completed, properly- formatted, printed script
并请务必于2月16日下午5时前
must be received by Paramount Pictures by
寄至派拉蒙电影公司"
5:00 pm on February 16th."
2月16 就是这周二
February 16th is this Tuesday.
今天是周日
Today is Sunday.
周日邮局没人来收信
There's no mail pickup on Sundays.
周一又过节了
And Monday is a holiday.
赶不上了
It's too late.
来不及了
那好
Okay.
有去洛杉矶的大巴
Buses go to Los Angeles.
我可以坐大巴前去洛杉矶
I could take a bus to Los Angeles.
去洛杉矶的车要多少钱?
How much will a bus to Los Angeles cost?
大概和321路一样吧
Probably the same as the 321 bus,
毕竟都是巴士
because it is also a bus.
去哪里要花多久时间?
How long will it take to get there?
不知道
I don't know.
我不知道
如果我忘了自己在哪儿怎么办
What if I forget where I am?
那我要是迷路了呢?
如果我要小便怎么办
What if I have to pee?
请等等
Please, stand by.
求求你了 请等等
Please, please, stand by.
我不能走夜路
I can't go out at night.
我必须等到天亮
I have to wait till sunrise.
几点天亮
When is sunrise?
请回答 企业号
"Come in, Enterprise...
企业号 我是斯波克
Enterprise, this is Spock."
回家 皮特
Go home, Pete.
你不能和我一起去洛杉矶的派拉蒙电影公司
You can't come with me to Paramount Pictures.
皮特 赶快回家
Go home, Pete!
你赢了
Okay.
但是你必须吃花生酱和果冻三明治
But you have to eat peanut butter and jelly sandwiches,
就像人一样
just like people do.
有人吗
Hello?
这是去洛杉矶的巴士吗
Does this bus go to Los Angeles?
这辆巴士去洛杉矶吗
这是去洛杉矶的巴士吗
Does this bus go to Los Angeles?
不到 你得去巴士中转站
No, you need to go to the Transbay Terminal
在弗里蒙特街上
on Fremont Street.
在市场街的另一边
That's on the other side of Market Street.
好的 谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
喂 喂 喂
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
走反了 在另一边
The other way, the other way!
好的 谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
温蒂
Wendy?
玛德琳
Madeline!
温蒂不在她的房间里
Wendy's not in her room.
我们必须去找她
We've got to find her.
好
Okay.
-温蒂 温蒂  -温蒂
- Wendy? Wendy? - Wendy?
温蒂
Wendy!
我们无论发生了什么都不准
We're not allowed to cross Market Street
横穿市场街
under any circumstances.
你需要买车票
You need a ticket.
什么
What?
你需要买车票才可以乘坐巴士
You need a ticket to ride the bus.
哦哦
Oh.
你
You...
需要
need...
喂 小姐
Hey, little missy...
赶紧去买票
Go buy a ticket!
你要去哪儿
Where you going?
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
你说什么
Excuse me?
-洛杉矶  -单程还是往返
- Los Angeles. - One way or round-trip?
什么
What?
你要待在那里还是打算回来
Are you staying there or are you coming back?
还回来
Coming back.
好的 往返车票 合计
Okay, round trip, that'll be...
86美元
86 dollars.
我买到票了
I've got a ticket.
是往返的内种 因为我还打算回来
It's a round-trip ticket because I'm coming back.
漂亮
Great.
能给我吗
Can I have it?
我们要安静一点 皮特
We have to be quiet, Pete,
不能打扰其他乘客
so that we don't disturb the other passengers.
妈妈 这个阿姨包里有个小狗狗
Mommy, there's a doggie in that lady's bag.
我懂 皮特 但是你必须要憋住
I know, Pete. But you've got to hold it.
好吧 我去问问
Okay, I'll ask.
不好意思 司机师傅
Excuse me, bus driver.
我的朋友想要小便
My friend needs to pee.
洗手间坏了
Restroom's broken.
告诉你朋友一个小时之内就能到下一站
Tell your friend the next stop's in an hour.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
不要这样 皮特
Don't do it, Pete!
这就是你在巴士上随便小便的下场
This is what happens when you pee on the bus.
哦 等一下
Oh, wait.
等一秒钟
One second.
喂
Hello?
嘿 奥德丽 我是斯考蒂
Hey, Audrey. It's Scottie here.
听着 我...
Listen, I...
我今儿早上来时候 发现温蒂并不在这里
I got in this morning and Wendy wasn't here.
那么她在哪儿？
Then, where is she?
我不知道
I don't know.
我建议你先待在家 万一她是跑去找你了
I suggest you stay put in case she's headed your way.
那你也不知道她在哪儿
So, you have no idea where she is?
呃...
Uh...
我等会儿再打给你
I'm gonna call you back.
巴士上的卫生间有故障
"Bus restrooms do not work."
没关系
It's okay.
她叫麦迪逊
Her name's Madison.
你好 麦迪逊
Hi, Madison.
我们有时候叫她玛蒂
We call her Maddy sometimes,
尤其是当她不高兴 或是哭的时候
especially when she gets upset and starts crying.
玛蒂非常非常可爱
Maddy's very, very cute.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也是一个姨妈 有个外甥女叫露比
I'm an aunt. I have a niece named Ruby.
-玛蒂有姨吗  -她有3个
- Does Maddy have an aunt? - She has three.
你喜欢当小姨的感觉么
Do you like being an aunt?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道
You don't know?
我从没见过露比
I've never met Ruby.
我姐姐害怕我会伤到她
My sister's afraid I might hurt her.
我之前经常发脾气
I used to have tantrums.
从什么时候开始
When was that?
从我小时候
When I was younger.
真令人难过啊
That's so sad.
但是我不能想象你会伤害一个婴儿
But I can't imagine you hurting a baby, not ever.
如果你愿意 你可以与我和玛蒂一起玩儿
You can hang out with me and Maddy if you want.
来吧
Come on.
就现在 来吧
Now, come on.
来 坐下
Come sit.
你打算要去哪儿呢
So, where are you headed?
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
我打算参加一个竞赛 一个写作大赛
I'm going to enter a contest, a writing contest.
我期待你能获奖
I hope you win.
我会为你祈祷的
I'm gonna say a little prayer for you.
哪种祈祷呢
What kind of prayer?
哦 我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
好的那一个
A good one.
别担心
Don't you worry.
怎么了
What's the matter?
给...
Here...
-你想抱抱她吗?  -不 我不行
- Do you wanna hold her? - No, no.
没关系
It's okay.
瞧瞧这只小可爱
Look at the puppy.
奥
Oh!
你想摸摸小狗
Wanna pet the puppy?
你知道吗 我和我男朋友
You know what, me and my boyfriend,
事实上正打算去洛杉矶
we're actually going down to L.A.
如果你没有车的话
So, if you don't have a ride,
也许你应该和我们一起去
maybe you should just come with us.
怎么样
Yeah?
你觉得呢
Would you like that?
我非常非常愿意
I'd like that very, very much.
好 那么
Okay, then.
走吧 朱尔斯
Let's go, Jules.
准备好了
You ready?
我得先灌满我的水瓶
I've got to fill up my water bottle first.
好
Okay.
-把它给我  -不要
- Give it to me! - No!
还回我的笔记本
Give me my notebook back!
把笔记本还给我
抱歉
I'm sorry.
他们偷走了我的iPod 皮特
They stole my iPod, Pete.
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee-lilee ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee lo ♪
♪ 嘿 小姑娘 不想和我出去兜风吗 ♪
♪ Hey, little gal, won't you come out with me? ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee lo ♪
♪ 我想让你看到这一面的自己 ♪
♪ This side of myself that I want you to see ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee lo ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee-lilee ♪
♪ 嘿 啦哩 啦哩 喽 ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee lo ♪
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee-lilee ♪
她的名字叫温蒂 • 维尔科特
Her name is Wendy Welcott.
哦 天呐 愿她平安无事
Oh, God, I hope she's okay.
♪ Hey, lilee-lilee ♪
嗨
Hi.
她已经坐上一辆去洛杉矶的巴士
So, she was on a bus heading to Los Angeles.
司机在走到5号州际公路的时候赶她下车了
The driver removed her just off the I-5.
-他们尝试定位具体地点  -什么
- They're trying to locate her. - What?
我们整竭尽所能的寻找蛛丝马迹
We are doing everything we can to find her.
如果她给你打电话 第一时间通知我 好吗
And if she calls you, let me know right away, okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
这些包士力架怎么卖
How much do all of these candy bars cost?
呃...
Uh...
美块儿一美元
A buck a piece.
上面写着18块儿 那么也就是共18美元
It says there are 18 inside, so that's $18.
对 就是18美元
Yeah, 18 dollars.
什么
What?
别弄虚作假 欺人太甚
Don't cheat her.
光天化日之下你心里也清楚 糖果也就2.99美元
That candy is $2.99 and you know it.
别用你内酸脸对我挤眉弄眼
Don't be looking at me with your squinched-up face.
你要是收了她的钱 就叫做偷窃
You were gonna take her money, and that's called stealing.
现在你向她道歉
Now you apologize.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这就对了
That's better.
亲爱的...
Honey...
别老让别人占你便宜 明白吗
Don't let people take advantage of you, okay?
我有个孙子也像你一样
I've got a grandson like you.
特别善良可亲的一个男孩
Sweetest boy in the world,
但是他一直整不明白这些花言巧语
but he always has trouble trying to figure it all out.
这是我的外甥女 露比
This is my niece, Ruby.
哦 她长得可真甜美
Oh, she's adorable!
那你的家人在哪儿
So, where's your family?
加利福尼亚州 奥克兰 安康路 992号
992 Heath Road, Oakland, California.
你是说你独自一人跑到这边来吗
You mean you're out here all by yourself?
不 我还有皮特和我待在一起
No, I have Pete with me.
我知道 可是谁在照顾你呢
Yeah, but who's taking care of you?
我自己
I am.
哦 亲爱的 这可不大可行
Oh, honey, that's not right.
你不应该独自外出来这儿的
You shouldn't be out here all by yourself.
你要不跟我一道吧
Why don't you come with me?
-你要去哪儿  -她去外面了
- Where are you going? - She's out there.
茕茕一人
Alone.
在这里和洛杉矶之间的某处
Somewhere between here and Los Angeles.
好吧 那又怎样 莫非你要开到州际公路上去找她吗
Okay, so what, you're just gonna drive down the interstate looking for her?
是 的确如此
Yeah, I am.
我不能只是待在这儿
I can't just sit here.
我要去找她
I'm going.
冰箱里还有很多母乳
There's plenty of breast milk in the fridge.
你是打算去派拉蒙电影公司做一个女演员吗
Are you going to Paramount Pictures to be an actress?
你颜值够格
You're pretty enough.
不 我是个作家
No, I'm a writer.
我写了个剧本
I wrote a script.
有427页长
It's 427 pages long.
哦 那么厉害
Oh, my goodness!
讲的是什么呢
What's it about?
讲的是两个老朋友分开了
It's about two old friends who are separated.
其中一个 斯波克 是个瓦肯人
And one of them, Spock, is a Vulcan.
他致力于发现如何有幽默感
He discovers how to have a sense of humor.
他专门剖析了笑话的结构
He makes a special study of the anatomy of jokes
这也是种古老的 原始的 瓦肯文化
which were a part of old, or primitive, Vulcan culture.
他根据过去的立体影像档案库
He relates different parts of a joke
把笑话分成了不同的部分
to different facial expressions
和不同的面部表情相联系...
according to old holographic archives...
他还发现幽默感的
and he figures out a scientific equation
科学方程式
for a sense of humor.
哦 我真希望我的孙子能见到你
Oh, I wish my grandson could meet you.
他肯定比我更明白你说的所有爆点
He would so get whatever it is you're talking about.
他会觉得你酷毙了
He would think you were pretty cool.
我希望自己能常见到他
I'd love to see him more myself.
但我们分隔两地
But I'm here and he's there.
你为什么不和他一起住呢？
Why don't you live with him?
我不想给别人添麻烦
I don't wanna be anybody's burden.
谁都有自己的生活
People have their own lives,
用不了多久 人家的生活里就没有你了
and after a while, those lives don't include you.
没错 她叫温蒂·沃尔科特
Yes, her name is Wendy Welcott.
21岁 1米64 金发
She's 21 years old. Five-foot-four, blonde.
谢谢了
Thanks anyway.
小姐？
Miss?
小姐？能听见我说话吗？
Miss? Can you hear me?
小姐？
Miss?
她在说什么？
What's she saying?
欢迎来到桂香卷
Welcome to Cinnabon.
您想尝一个桂香卷吗？
Would you like to try a Cinnabon?
没骨折也没出血
No fractures, no bleedings.
可能有轻微脑震荡
Suspected mild concussion.
他们想让她住院一两天
They wanna keep her for a day or two,
但我们也只是照顾一张病床而已
but we're just waiting on a bed.
能把她的表格给我吗？
Would you mind grabbing her chart?
我必须得走
I have to go.
我要走
I want to go.
我必须得走
I have to go.
我找温蒂·沃尔科特
Wendy Welcott.
我们这儿有4个无名女子
We've got four Jane Does in here.
好吧 她身高1米64 一头金发
Well, she's five-foot-four, blonde.
4个都是金发
They've all got blonde hair.
都差不多1米6多
They're all five-foot-something.
这儿还有只无名狗
Hell, we even have a Jane Dog in here.
等等 你刚说什么？
Wait, what did you just say?
我们这儿还有只无名狗
We've got a Jane Dog here.
还是公的
John Dog.
它是不是穿着星际迷航服？
Is he wearing a Star Trek uniform?
啥？
A what?
星际迷航制服 它穿了吗？
A Star Trek uniform. Is he wearing one?
哦 没错 是穿了！
Oh, yeah, he is!
啊 看呐！
Ah, look at that!
太可爱了
That's so cute.
那么 你的具体位置是哪儿？
Okay, where are you again, exactly?
嘿 起床
Hey, wake up.
穿上衣服 跟我走
I need you to get dressed. You're coming with me.
妈 怎么了？
Mom, what's going on?
呃 我的一个病人逃走了 先穿衣服吧
Oh, a patient of mine ran away. So, please just go get dressed.
我们去哪儿？
Where are we even going?
贝克斯菲尔德
Bakersfield.
啥？
What?
她正赶往洛杉矶想投一个剧本
She's trying to get to L.A. and turn in a script
参加一个比赛
for this competition.
写的不错吗？
Is it any good?
-什么？ -那个剧本
- What? - The script.
哦 我只读过几页
Oh, I could only get a few pages in.
没看懂
I don't get it.
什么让你看不懂？
What don't you get?
好吧 我知道他是星球大战的英雄
Okay, so, I know he's the hero of Star Wars,
但那个叫科克的到底是谁？
but who exactly is this Kirk person?
咱现在就撞车吧因为咱俩太死有应得了!
Please, crash this car right now because we both deserve to die!
山姆！
Sam!
在星球大战里...
In Star Trek...
- 嗯 -詹姆斯·T·柯克是
- Okay. - James T. Kirk is the captain
企业号的舰长
of the starship Enterprise.
好吧 那是他们乘的飞船 对吧？
Right, that's the spaceship they're on, right?
对 对 是飞船 好样的 妈
Yes, yes, the spaceship. Great job, Mom.
但她为什么那么痴迷？
But why does she find it so fascinating?
我也不明白
That's what I don't get.
我不知道 或许是因为那些角色吧
I don't know. Maybe it's the characters.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
拿史波克来说吧
Like Spock, for example.
他是半人类半外星人
He's half-human, half-alien.
不能很好的处理情感
He has trouble dealing with his emotions.
哪儿这么说的？
Where did it say that?
他就是这样的人设
That's just how he is.
祝你愉快 都好吧？
Have a good one, okay?
你要去C病房
You are going to Ward C.
我不去C病房
I don't want to go to Ward C.
我要去派拉蒙公司
I want to go to Paramount Pictures.
额 很抱歉 小女孩
Well, I'm sorry, little lady,
看起来你要去的是C病房
it looks like you are going to Ward C.
我在哪？
Where am I?
你在医院 撞到了头
You're at the hospital. You hit your head.
皮特呢？
Where's Pete?
-我的狗狗在哪儿？ -它没事
- Where's my dog? - He's okay.
护士在照看它 还给它洗了澡
The nurses have him. They gave him a little bath.
我们走吧 怎么样？
Let's get you outta here, huh?
出发喽
Away we go.
我想嘘嘘
I've got to pee.
我们到楼上你再嘘嘘 好吗？
You can pee when we get you upstairs, all right?
不 我现在就想嘘嘘
No, I've got to pee right now.
就现在 我要嘘嘘
Right now, I've got to pee.
- 立刻 -好吧 好 好
- Right now. - All right, okay, okay.
快一点哦
Let's make it quick.
我听说你把警察吓坏了
I heard you scared the crap out of a cop.
我老爸就是警察
My dad was a cop.
哦 他还留着八字胡呢
Yeah, he had this walrus moustache and everything.
我们小时候调皮捣蛋
When we were kids and we misbehaved,
他常给我们记过
he used to give us demerits.
“你装错子弹了 记过一次”
"You loaded my gun wrong. That's a demerit."
“猫王唱片搞错了 记过”
"It's the wrong Elvis record. Demerit."
“衣服丢在地上了 记过”
"Clothes on the floor. Demerit."
要是足够幸运 记的过足够多
And if you were lucky enough to get enough demerits,
就得睡小黑屋
you had to sleep in the shed.
甚至现在每当我回家 他也总是说
Even now when I come home, he's like,
“你最好赶快搬出去
"You'd better move out of the house soon,
否则让你睡小黑屋”
or I'm gonna make you sleep in the shed."
别说了！
Cut it out!
一点也不好笑
That's not a funny thing to joke about.
你知道 我是你儿子
You know, I'm your son.
尊重我一下 别再开这种玩笑
Show me a little respect. Don't joke like that.
别再开玩笑了
Just quit kidding around.
你在里面还好吧？
You all good in there?
你嘘的时间有点长
That's a long pee.
那 我要进去了 没关系吧？
Okay, I'm gonna come inside, all right?
我进来了哦！
I'm coming in!
她跳窗跑了！
She jumped out the window!
我会回来找你的 皮特
I'll come back for you, Pete.
温蒂！
Wendy!
嘿！
Hey!
嗯 我立刻出发
Yeah, I'm on my way right now.
哦 天啊！
Oh, my God!
哦 我的剧本！
Oh, my script!
我的剧本...
My script...
我的...
My...
嘿！站住！
Hey! Stop!
妈妈..
Mom...
这是温蒂的剧本
This is Wendy's script.
温蒂？
Wendy?
温蒂！
Wendy!
您得冷静点
You need to calm down.
眼下生气也没用
Getting angry is not gonna help the situation.
嘿 我没生气
Hey, I am not angry.
这儿没人生气
Nobody's angry here.
我只是在试着理解
I'm just trying to figure out
你们这些人到底怎么回事！
what the hell is wrong with you people!
哇哦 这就简单了 来
Whoa, easy now. Come on, Scottie.
我们很好 夫人 但是鉴于
Nothing is wrong with us, ma'am, but given the way
你说的是我 我猜是您有问题
you're speaking to me, I guess something must wrong with you.
嘿！
Hey!
小心你的脸出问题
Something's gonna be wrong with your face
要是你再这样对我妈讲话！
if you don't stop talking to my mom like that!
请你们都冷静一下
I'm gonna need the both of you to calm down.
抱歉 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
但这简直难以接受
but this is just completely unacceptable.
我妹妹呢？
Where's my sister?
-你是沃尔科特小姐吗？ -是的 温蒂呢？
- Are you Ms. Welcott? - Yeah. Where's Wendy?
很抱歉 但是...
I am sorry, but...
她从值班护士眼皮子底下溜走了
she slipped by the duty nurse.
我们现在也不知道她在哪儿
We have no idea how,
但我们四处找过她
but we've looked everywhere for her.
现在整个州的警察
We've got officers up and down the state
都在帮忙找她
looking for her now.
她在这儿到底怎么了？她受伤了？
What was she doing here anyway? Was she hurt?
她怎么从你们这儿溜走的？
How did she get away from you people?
有人能告诉我我妹到底怎么了吗？
Can anybody tell me anything about my sister?
“格式正确的完整打印剧本
"Your completed, properly formatted, printed script
必须于2月16日下午5时前收悉”
must be received by February 16th, 5:00 pm."
“格式正确的完整打印剧本
"Your completed, properly formatted, printed script
必须于2月16日下午5时前收悉”
must be received by February 16th, 5:00 pm."
“格式正确的完整打印剧本
"Your completed, properly formatted, printed script...
必须于2月16日下午5时前收悉”
must be received by February 16th, 5:00 pm."
敬请...
Please...
稍候
stand by.
请稍候
Please, stand by.
我的剧本
My script.
没了
It's gone.
“舰长...
"Captain...
只有一个逻辑方向可供..
there is only one logical direction in which to go...
前进”
Forward."
“舰长日志...
"Captain's log...
最后的记录
Final entry.
‘企业号估计遇难了
'The Enterprise is presumed lost.
我和史波克是唯一的幸存者
Spock and I are the sole survivors.
我们的命运如何依然未知’
Our destiny, unknown.'
史波克抬头仰望漫天星空...
Spock looks up at the star-filled sky...
凝视着这片贫瘠的外星荒原
surveys the barren contours of this alien wasteland.
窥视着这黑暗深渊...
Peering into the murky abyss...
他看到了以前从未见过的东西”
Spock saw something he had never seen before."
或许是我的错
Maybe this is my fault.
“必须要逃离这里...
"Escape is imperative...
史波克将垂死的柯克揽入怀中
Spock cradles the dying Kirk in his arms.
他的舰长也是他的朋友
His captain. His friend.
柯克仰头望着他 眼神渐渐黯淡无光”
Kirk looks up at him, the light dimming in his eyes."
你知道公交车站在哪儿吗？
Do you know where the bus station is?
“‘我害怕 史波克’
"'I'm afraid, Spock.'
史波克冷静的安慰道
Spock is calm, reassuring.
‘别怕 吉姆’
'Don't be afraid, Jim.
未知是等待我们去征服的 不是让我们害怕的’”
The unknown is there for us to conquer, not to fear.'"
去洛杉矶我得买票吗？
Do I need a ticket to ride the bus to Los Angeles?
是的 得买
Yes, you do.
但是下一班车是明早八点
But the next one is not until 8:00 am tomorrow.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
距离八点还有11小时13分钟
8:00 am is in 11 hours and 13 minutes.
我可以等
I'll wait.
“他在虚空中跌跌撞撞的前行
"Slowly tumbling through the emptiness of space...
宇航服上的灯光
the lights of his spacesuit
在黑暗中照亮了他”
illuminating him in the darkness."
你也睡不着？
You can't sleep either?
“光线些微 独身一人...
"Tiny, alone...
茫茫大海中的一束微光
a single speck of light in a sea of night.
第一次...
For the first time...
没有故事...
No stories...
也无人回应...
No echoes...
大脑一片空白
Nothing in his head.
唯有沉寂一片”
Just silence."
沉寂
Silence.
我希望她没事
I hope she's okay.
她是个善于随机应变的女孩
She's a very resourceful girl.
说实话 我也有点吃惊
To tell you the truth, I'm kind of impressed.
她以前什么都怕
She used to be afraid of everything.
这一次出远门对她来说不容易
This can't be easy for her.
或许我小瞧了她
Maybe I underestimated her.
你妹妹...
Your sister...
是我见过的最难懂又最有创造力的人
is one of the most complex and creative people I know.
是啊
Yeah.
我是说 她并不总是那么容易让人猜透
I mean, she's not always that easy to figure out.
不过有一点是肯定的 她绝对能考验你的耐心
She can really try your patience, that's for sure.
是啊
Yeah.
我妈妈对她足够耐心了
My mother was so patient with her.
她一个人把我们两个带大
She took care of both of us, by herself.
- 单亲妈妈？ - 对
- Single mom? - Yeah.
没错
Yeah.
妈妈死后 我尽全力
After our mother died, I tried my best
来照顾Wendy
to take care of Wendy.
但我马上要结婚了
But then I got married,
我们发现 我们将要有孩子了
we found out we were gonna have a baby.
我总是感到惊奇 对于很多人来说怎么能如此容易
I'm always amazed by how easy it is for some people
掌控这一切
to be able to handle it all.
小姐？
Miss?
很抱歉 可是我们要关门了
I'm sorry, but I need to close up.
你要去什么地方吗？
Do you have any place to go?
派拉蒙电影公司
Paramount Pictures.
我可以在门口等去LA的巴士吗？
Can I wait outside for the bus to Los Angeles?
当然了 我可没法阻止你
Well, I can't stop you.
但你要小心
But you be careful, okay?
我很小心
I am careful.
当标志上写着“请勿通过” 我就不会走过去
I don't walk when the sign says, "Don't walk", and...
我只穿过步行街一次
I only crossed Market Street one time.
好吧
Okay.
进浴室
Go into bathroom.
洗个澡
Take a shower.
这里没有淋浴
There is no shower.
没关系
That's okay.
一次不洗没关系 但两次就不可以
It's okay to skip once, but not twice.
玛德琳是这么说的
Madeline said so.
我得换个衣服
I've got to change.
我需要买张去LA的机票 谢谢
I need to buy a ticket to Los Angeles, please.
这需要22美元
That'll be 22 dollars.
这些钱不够的
That's not going to be enough money.
我只有七块五毛二 我数过了
It's $7.52, I counted it.
- 下一个 - 但是这些钱差不多了
- Next. - But it's almost enough.
我今天必须赶到LA
I need to get to Los Angeles today
因为今天是比赛的最后期限
because today is the contest deadline.
我知道七块五毛二是不够 但是有没有办法……
$7.52 is not enough, I know, but is there some way that...
下一位 谢谢
Next customer, please.
请您…通融一下…好吗？
Can it be enough? Please.
就这一次？
Just for today?
你挡着别人的道了
You're holding up the line.
下一个
Let's keep moving.
有什么消息吗？
Any news?
在哪里可以乘去Lankershim的巴士？
Where do you get on the Lankershim bus?
那是她吗？
That her?
你知道在哪里可以乘去Lankershim的巴士吗？
Do you know where you get on the Lankershim bus?
那就是她
That's her.
嗨 小姐？
Hey, miss?
小姐？
Miss?
喂！喂！
Hey! Hey!
停下！
Stop!
回去 回车上 回车上再说
Back in, back in, back in.
没事 没事
All right, all right.
温蒂
Wendy.
温蒂 出来吧 我们不会伤害你的
Wendy, come out. We won't hurt you.
- 我觉得她在那里 - 等一下
- I think she's in there. - Just, just...
你会吓到她的 好吗？
You'll spook her, okay?
温蒂
Wendy.
温蒂！
Wendy!
我们是朋友 出来吧
走开！
出来吧
我跟你是一伙儿的
我不相信你
勇士从不让他的朋友独处险境
我要去派拉蒙电影公司
我知道 让我先带你去个安全的地方
好了 好了 你安全了
嘿 你可真有两下子 这是什么语言？
Hey, man, what language is that?
别提了道尔 这没什么了不起的 好吗？
Forget about it, Doyle. It's nothing, okay?
我还不知道你会外语呢 老兄！
I didn't know you spoke a foreign language, bro.
这到底是什么语言啊？
What was that?
克林贡语 明白了吗？
Klingon, all right?
- 天哪！ - 闭嘴道尔
- Damn! - Shut up, Doyle.
好的 我说英语
Yes, I speak English.
他们找到她了
They found her!
她现在在洛杉矶市中心的警察局
She's at a police station in downtown L.A.
萨姆！
Sam!
所以 后来发生了什么？
So, what happens next?
斯波克开始体验七年之痒
Spock starts to experience the pon farr.
在他经历的这么多事之后？
On top of everything else he's going through?
是的
Yes.
他所有的情感都迸发出来
And all of his emotions rise to the surface
然后这些情感…开始把他撕成碎片
and they start tearing him apart,
他不得不搞清楚如何控制他们
and he has to figure out how to control them.
这太棒了
That's amazing.
这太了不起了！
That's amazing!
但我赶不上了
But I'm not going to make it.
还有超过100页的剧本不见了
There's still over 100 pages missing.
噢 温蒂！
Oh, Wendy.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我一直都很担心你
I've been so worried about you.
噢天哪 我们都担心死了
Oh, God, we were worried sick about you!
我们怎么说的来着 关于穿过步行街？
What did we say about crossing Market Street?
在任何情况下我都不许穿过步行街
I'm not allowed to cross Market Street under any circumstances.
我们找到了你的剧本
We found your script.
我们还可以赶上！
We can still make it.
祝你成功 温蒂
Qapla', Wendy.
也祝你成功 弗兰克
Qapla', Frank, yaS.
嘿 我真的很喜欢你的剧本
Hey, I really liked your script.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是说 你的剧本真的很棒
Yeah. Yeah, I mean, it was really good.
当斯波克不得不回到过去
When Spock has to travel back in time
带着灵药去拯救所有人
with the Elixir of Light to save everyone,
他目睹了所有他爱的人死去 不是吗？
he sees all these people that he loves die, right?
甚至柯克
Even Kirk.
他也想要去救他们所有人 但他做不到
And he wants to save all of them, too, but he can't,
因为他知道他们是为了真理而献身的
because he knows they died for something good.
我真的觉得你一定能赢
I really think it could win.
你得在前面拐弯
You need to get over.
我留给你的花生酱三明治
Did you get that peanut butter
你吃了么？
and jelly sandwich that I left you?
我真的好想你
I missed you a lot.
妈妈 就在这里 在这里拐弯
Mom, it's right here. Turn here.
就是这里！停车！
There it is! Stop the car!
- 温蒂！停下！ - 快去 温蒂！
- Wendy! Stop! - Go, Wendy!
算了 让她去吧 她会没事的
No, let her go. She'll be okay.
我现在不能走过去
I can't walk.
所有人请跟紧了
Everyone stay in the group, please.
现在我们看到的 是拍摄《印第安纳琼斯》的摄影棚
Now, over here is the soundstage where they shot "Indiana Jones."
请问
Excuse me.
你知道1500号建筑在哪里吗？
Do you know where Building 1500 is?
当然 直着走然后右拐
Yeah, it's just up and to the right.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我来交我的剧本
I need to drop off my script.
嗯…你不能交到这里
Ah, yeah, you can't drop that off here.
“你的剧本必须在2月16日下午五点前提交”
"Your script must be received by February 16th at 5:00 pm."
没错 但我们只接受信件形式
Yes, and we only accept entries by mail.
知道吗？
Okay?
可这里是收发室
But this is the mailroom.
你看…
Look...
我们不接受个人提交
We don't accept personal deliveries.
所有的剧本必须盖上邮戳 再寄过来
All scripts must be postmarked and mailed.
没有例外 好吗？
No exceptions, okay?
胡扯
Piece of shit...
你知道写点东西有多么难吗？
Do you know how hard it is to write something?
你知道写作有多么难吗？
你知道写一部作品有多么难吗？
Do you know how hard it is to write something?
所有的思考和策划
All the thinking and planning
一遍遍重写那些你已经写过的内容
and re-writing of everything you already wrote
只为了让别人读到？
for somebody else to read?
每一个竭力思索的日日夜夜
All the nights and days spent thinking?
思索如何用正确的词句来表达
Thinking about the right words to say...
思索最好的方式来表达
thinking about the best way to say them?
因为你想去讲述的那个故事 对你来说有多么重要
Because the story you wanna tell means so much to you?
写出那些剧本的所有人
All those people that wrote those scripts,
有人能看到他们
somebody's going to read them.
我只想要一个机会！
And I just want a chance!
就像其他人一样！
Just like everyone else got!
来人！叫保安！
Somebody call security.
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
你说什么？
What did you just say?
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
不知道
No.
那太好了
Good.
喂！
Hey!
喂 停下！
Hey, stop!
谢谢
Thanks.
所以你交上去了？
So did it get in?
噢 温蒂！
Oh, Wendy!
温蒂 你做到了！
Wendy, you did it!
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
- 谢谢 - 没事
- Thank you. - Oh, yeah.
再见
Bye.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
你全凭自己写完了整个剧本！
You turned in that script all by yourself.
你说你想要让他们看到
You said you wanted to show them...
你做到了
and you did.
但我想要让你看到
But I wanted to show you.
是啊
Yeah.
我的iPod丢了
My iPod was stolen.
我会给你买个新的
I'll get you a new one.
真的吗？
You will?
我很感激
I'd really appreciate that.
温蒂 我一直在想…
Wendy, I've been thinking...
并且
And...
我一直想弄清楚
I've been trying to figure out...
妈妈到底想要我们做什么
what Mom would have wanted for us.
妈妈已经去世了
Well, Mom's dead.
所以 她不再有任何想法了
So, she doesn't want anything anymore.
来啊 船长 我们可以做到的
"'Come on, Captain. We can do this together.
不要放弃
Don't give up now.
他们的最后时刻到来了
Their final moment had come.
已经没有回头路了
There was no going back.
一息尚存之际 柯克掀起他的面罩
With his dying breath, Kirk lifts his visor.
斯波克最后一次 注视着他朋友的双眸
Spock looks into his friend's eyes for the last time.
柯克明白 是时候让斯波克解脱了
Kirk knows it is time to set Spock free.
让他自由的去追寻他的初心
Free to find his human heart.
结束
The End.
全剧终
Epilogue.
一切都会好起来的
Everything would be okay.
斯科蒂这样说道
Scottie had said so.
但那些小光点在哪里呢？
But where was that tiny speck of light
那些穿梭在宇宙中的小光点
traveling through the universe?
那些和别人不一样的小光点
Different from the others...
想要去到想去的地方
hoping to get where it's going?
想要去到心之所向的地方
To where it belongs?
亲爱的温蒂
"Dear Wendy...
感谢你参加
Thank you for submitting your script
‘星际迷航：大胆去写’比赛
to the 'Star Trek: To Boldly Go Writing Competition.'
我读了你的剧本
I've been reading your script.
你是个很优秀的作家
You're an excellent writer.
你真的很优秀
You really are.
谢谢你 斯科蒂
Thank you, Scottie.
不客气 温蒂
You're welcome, Wendy.
“我们写这封信 是为了感谢你
"We are writing to thank you
愿意与我们分享你的故事
for sharing your story with us.
我们被你展现出的
We are thrilled with the talent and hard work
才华与努力所震惊
that you have displayed."
这是给你的
This is for you.
哇 谢谢
Jeez, thanks.
诶 对了…
Uh, hey...
你去参加了那个创作比赛吗？
Did you ever turn your script into the contest?
什么时候能知道结果？
When will you find out if you've won?
很快
Soon.
- 祝你好运 - 祝我好运
- Fingers crossed. - Fingers crossed.
“很抱歉你的剧本
"Unfortunately, your script was not selected
没能赢得比赛
as one of the winners...
但是请不要气馁
But please do not be discouraged.
永远不要辍笔
Never stop writing...
永远不要放弃分享你的故事
Never stop telling your story.
我们希望在未来可以读到你的更多作品
We hope to read more of your work someday.
在那之前
Until then...
生生不息 繁荣昌盛
live long and prosper."
嗨 鲁比
Hi, Ruby.
我可以抱抱她吗？
Can I hold her, please?